

□ 425-241-9772 | ■ andrew.zhao.luo@gmail.com | 🛅 andrew-zhao-luo

Summary ____

Engineer with interest in machine learning systems, compilers, and performance. Has experience in writing compilers to make it easier to make machine learning systems run fast. Proficient in **Python, C/C++**, working knowledge of **CUDA**, and experience with **MLIR**. Enjoys solving problems, quickly iterating, and taking ownership in ambiguous environments.

Experience _

Senior Compiler Engineer

Seattle, WA

MODULAR AI, CORE TECHNOLOGIES

Jun. 2023 - Now

- Top contributor in the past year (by commits) on a team of 10 to a MLIR based compiler for deep learning models.
- · Major contributor to shape propagation, quantization, and programmability systems of compiler.
- Lead efforts around inter-operability with Mojo with a group of 7 engineers in creating a Triton-lang like experience.

Staff Engineer Seattle, WA

OCTOML, APPLIED COMPILER ENGINEERING - PERFORMANCE

Mar. 2021 - Jun. 2023

- Official committer to Apache TVM (9.2k stars on GitHub), an open source autotuning compiler written in C++ and Python.
- Contribute quantization, mixed precision, ONNX support in TVM. Write kernels and benchmarking tools to improve iteration.
- Implementing features in SaaS product such as compiler cache, adding new tuning algorithms, and lowering resource usage.

Machine Learning Engineer

Seattle, WA

APPLE, AI/ML MACHINE INTELLIGENCE NEURAL DESIGN

Jan. 2020 - Mar. 2021

- Using quantization, sparsity, and hardware-specific knowledge to train models for Siri, Homepod, and future products
- Developing in-house solutions for training vision models and deploying/benchmarking on FPGA and ASIC environments
- Developing demos show-casing technologies to internal stake-holders.

XNOR.AI, MACHINE LEARNING TEAM (ACQUIRED BY APPLE)

Aug. 2019 - Jan 2020

- Training performant computer vision models that can run on bespoke and edge hardware. Part time until Jan 2019.
- Creating demos showcasing XNOR's technologies to key executives at major tech companies.

Education

University of Washington

Seattle, WA

DOUBLE MAJOR IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING AND BIOENGINEERING

Sep. 2015 - Jun. 2019

- Coursework: Machine Learning, Probability and Statistics, Real Analysis, Operating Systems, Compilers, Embedded Systems
- GPA: 3.95, Summa Cum Laude

Projects and Potpourri

PAST INTERNSHIPS

Summers 2015-2018

- Sift: I rewrote HBase snapshot system, saving over \$1.5 million in \$3 costs a year and integrated data store with BigQuery.
- Facebook: I implemented statistical models to predict ad reach demographics for customers with multi-million yearly spend
- The Institute For Systems Biology: I helped scientists analyze large datasets of gene expression data.

PROJECT: FPGA IMAGE CONVOLUTION PHOTOBOOTH

2019

- Implemented streaming algorithm to run kernel convolutions on streamed images, implemented in FPGA on Altera Cyclone V
- · Integrated with camera and VGA, creating a variety of filters like Sobel edge detector, Gaussian blur, and image sharpening

PUBLICATION 2017

Automatic Characterization of User Errors in Spirometry. **Andrew Luo**, Eric Whitmire, James Stout, Drew Martenson, Shwetak Patel. *IEEE EMBC 2017 (Oral Presentation + Paper)*

PATENT APPLICATION 2020

Compressed Neural Network Models. US Patent App. 16/788261. James Gabriel et al. and Andrew Luo. Filed 13 August 2020.